Here's the energy level and the mood.
It is a light mode.
And I have even have a search field to search for things.
I can see the insights.
It even created an inside folder where you already can over time track your mood and energy.
And this is out of the box.
There's no application behind this.
It is just extracting what we will fill in from now onwards into this database.
If you're like me and you always struggle to make daily journaling, this video is for you because it
will change everything for you into your personal life. I have no doubt about this. I never saw the
reason to make real daily journaling. But what I have done is using the application day one
since 2018 because here is where I started the Paypal as movement which you might know as my icon now
and this YouTube channel talking about productivity tools, note-taking apps and so on
and this is where I saved my conclusions. So I started just writing down highlights and lowlights
but not daily journaling. So here for example I started my first online store and this is in
German now. So or here I was featured on note shelf on their website or here when I started
accelerating I created my first merge of the paypless movement. That was my first merge that
I did this. See all the remembrings are here.
So here my whole journey about going through the paperless movement,
growing the paperless movement, insights from the paperless movement,
building a business. This is what I was journaling about, but only if there are really relevant
insights like here when I launched the very first forum and in 2019 when I launched a membership and many things.
But the beautiful thing about this is that there was serendipity.
So if I go here on this day, you see there are five entries.
And these entries are from different journals that I have on the side and here is the new
YouTube strategy that I launched in 2024.
Here is my woodwork that I started and I built my own table.
And this is eight years ago when I brought my child for the first time to the kindergarten and
And many things like this that I loved to see on a daily basis what happened all the years ago.
And this is where I kept using day one and I kept it very clean because I didn't want to get random information about what I ate that day or how I was feeling that day.
So I always only saw milestones and highlights that are really relevant for me to see over time.
When I was for example celebrating the first 1000 subscribers on this YouTube channel and I see this every year,
I stay humble when we're now reaching the 100,000 subscribers after all this time and work that I put into this channel.
So you see, I used...
They won for such a long time, let's say since 2018 until now, which includes eight years of information that I shared there that are very personal insights, but they are still hidden in there.
I wasn't growing based on this.
I got this reminders and I saw the serendipity, but I wasn't concluding anything out of this journey.
And this is what AI changed.
And this is why along with day one, I started using Mindsera,
which is an AI based journaling application where you can share your thoughts
and AI will give you feedback.
And already back in 2025 with Claude Code,
I built my own AI agent I was able to talk to based on stoicism.
It was giving me recommendations and all these things I'm not even sharing here,
but it's all possible.
And besides Mindsera, I also used Stoic.
it is another journaling app that is a combination it looks more like the day one but with AI integrations
well I tested them all and the thing is your knowledge stays stuck in there and you cannot
have the context with everything around you going on and this is what
Claude code really changed in this game.
Now in this video, I want to show you how easy it became to do journaling, why it's worth
to now daily journaling, and how you can all build this just on a local folder on your computer.
So let's dive right into this, how we built this from scratch.
Now if we go into my own assistant here, and I open up my personal version that I have here,
I have a journaling app here.
It's not an app, it's just visualizing the database.
And that's what we will build today.
Something similar.
So here I'm able to simply share a screenshot and talk to AI and it will extract everything.
The mood I had when I was doing this, the energy levels that I had.
And then overall, it gives me even then a recommendation based on stoicism and so on moving forward.
This is an absolute game changer and whatever comes to mind or insights I get I can now share here and have this organized and cross connected with all my other thoughts that I had and people that I'm interacting with that I would have never received in any other applications that I paid money for.
So let's dive into how we build this from scratch. In a previous video I showed you already how we build from scratch this pk demo folder here where we build from the ground up how to have an owner's inbox that gets processed, how to have a basic team of AI agents working for you.
all the things you might have seen the video already if not it's worth going back there after
this video to get more details about how the basics work if we open this up you see it's again
just a simple website that opens up and looks and shares and this is what we built in this other video
and there was already a journal in there where we had a test with the first journal entry we had already contexts
contacts. We had already prefilled it with some contacts that we had there.
And here's Paco that we added here and so on. This is what we built in the past video.
And I could now build on top of this. However, in this video, I want to start from scratch with
focus just on this daily journal so we keep things clean. And in the end of the video,
I show you how you can easily do things like this
to have a sandbox mode to play around with things like this and merge it back into your actual team
that you already built previously so without further ado let's dive into this we just create
a new folder here on desktop called daily journaling and as you can see we open it up
it's an empty folder right here we could now just search for the terminal and start
Claude and I see already people who didn't watch the previous video say oh my god he's using Claude
code and now I have to learn code and all these things to make this journal work. Bear with me
watch the video until the end and you will see no code involved. This is the amazing thing about this
and what I'm sharing here you can also do on the desktop version go to co-work or even better code and just
Find this empty folder that we just created here.
If you want to follow along and you don't want to use the terminal, you can give it a go there too.
So you just open this folder daily journaling in here and this is it.
And you can do the same things that I'm doing now using the terminal.
I just prefer this way of working.
I feel it's more reliable and more efficient using the terminal.
And in fact, I showed you in another video that I'm not even only using the terminal,
but I'm using VS code, which again implies that there is code involved,
which I also demystified in another video.
That's not true.
You just open this folder and I will link all the videos to these things.
in the description below. But all I need to do here is open up this new folder, daily journaling,
in VS Code. And now you see it's just here representing the folder. So if you see there
is now the empty folder, we have clore code here, which is the extension, we can stay in this version
or we launch a terminal. And that's what I will do. I close this extension, which has a nice interface.
You know, that's very personal preferences. I just like to work in the terminal for now. I go on top
I click on new terminal or you use the shortcut.
It opens up the terminal.
I can write down Claude.
And in fact, I will with Claude dangerously skip permissions.
And there's also a new auto mode that is similar to this one.
And here, if you are unsure and you're scared what it will do with your system,
don't do this, right?
But I'm confident I'm working in this one folder here and I just don't like to accept all the basic access that is asking for all the time.
And that's why I want to use this version.
I see we are already running out of context, so I probably go over for this video.
I've done a lot of coding work today and a lot of things that are very token intensive.
But what we are building here today is nothing complex at all and you're not using up all your tokens at all.
Okay, so I will just move this box on here as I showed you in the other video.
Again, watch the video after this one if you want to get started.
Here it's all about building this journaling application.
So now what we see, we have here Claude Code open.
We have here our text entry and then here we have our empty folder.
And you just start talking to Claude.
In fact, in Claude Code you can just...
press and hold the spacebar to talk to Claude.
Hey, I just wanted to work on something.
Can you help me?
But I think it's not reliable enough.
And what I'm using to talk to Claude code is actually Whisperflow.
I made a dedicated video about Whisperflow already, how I talk to AI.
If you want to watch this, it's on the channel too.
So I have a shortcut and I can start talking.
And the good thing about Whisperflow is that all the things that I say is remains accessible.
okay and you have a dictionary where you can share the words that you're constantly using it even
updates itself in many things that i can do with whisper flow that the normal voice input from
cloud code is not capable of and usually messes things up and even if you have
things that you correct yourself along the way or bullet lists whisper flow
formats and reorganizes the things along the way.
That's just as a side note.
So you're not surprised when I keep talking to Claude and suddenly there's text
appearing, that's what I'm using.
All right, we are here in an empty folder and what I want to have,
I want to build a daily journaling database.
It's important.
that we are not saying something like a daily journaling application because then Claude will start building an actual application with code and all the things.
That's all overkill, something we don't need.
All we need is just say a local database and Claude will very likely create an SQLite, that's what it's called, database there.
Just describe what you need and what AI should avoid and you get there anyway.
So that's what I will keep doing here. Let's not overkill the things the moment you get started with
individual features like daily journaling here. Because you can always add later on,
but it's really harder to remove the features once you let them out all the things that you want,
all the bells and whistles. It also makes it harder for AI to get the full scope,
to really understand how everything works together. So build something very basic,
start using it and then you can give feedback how it should get improved.
And that's what's called continuous improvement.
And that's what we will do here too.
I want to have something lightweight on a local folder,
no complex application or anything like this.
It should be simply a database with a table where you track my thoughts
that I share with you and extract
my mood and my energy levels that you feel that my shared information contains. What I also want is
that I'm able to share images with you that I get also stored in this database. Okay see this is
what I have said here that's the prompt if you want to copy paste it feel free.
But again you see there's no prompt engineering that I'm doing or anything like this
Claude became really smart enough to really get the point what you're going for
and you can always revert things back and adjust things along the way
if you see the outcome is not proper and that's why I love working in VS Code
because I always have the connection of my input
and the output appearing inside this folder.
Again, keep in mind, this is just a local folder on our desktop called daily journaling.
So let's see what happens.
So I don't want to directly let them create everything.
And that's the big difference in Cloud Code that you can switch to plan mode that
will switch the approach of Claude to planning things really out so you can review first what
it's about to do and then you can confirm or readjust along the way. It also allows Claude
to ask you any clarifying questions along the way before it starts implementing.
And that's why I always recommend for when you get started, first start with the plan mode.
How I switched, it says is here, shift tap to cycle.
That's where you can switch between the different modes.
And let's see what plan it will come up with.
Now you see already, I didn't mention SQLite at all, but it says already a local SQLite database is the perfect fit here.
That's what I told you.
See, I didn't mention SQLite at all in my prompt, but it probably will always go.
get back to SQLite for a local database.
So even without understanding what SQLite database means,
you can be sure it will pick it up and it's the standard for these things.
And here's the plan: local daily journaling database.
Context, what I want, the table it will create in this database.
So the database will be called journal.db.
the table with the entry you see here all the context the mood the energy score the summary
tags even added. Now I have another table for the images that I mentioned that's the file structure
here and then how it works Thomas. So you can really step by step go through this and understand what
is going on and what it is about to implement. Now you could just say yes bypass permission or you go down here
and say anything that it should update or that was misunderstood.
And that's really the crucial step here, because this is the perfect moment
where you can make clear what you actually want from AI.
But I think it made an amazing job out of the box and we will just start implementing this.
So now you see it will start cleaning the context.
So it has a full context window available and it will use this plan
file to implement this now.
And then we see already here the first
folder appeared here we have the journalDB appearing so you see here will be our images that
are stored and it creates now this database and if we go to the desktop here that's the folder on
desktop you see in parallel it just creates the same thing so if people are always confused when
they hear about cloud code or vs code and it looks so technical and for developers only
Once you understand that this is just a more raw version of what is fancy in the front end, it makes it so much easier to use and a lot more powerful to control your AI and know where you're working in and many other things that we talk on this channel, but also in our membership in much more detail inside our courses and discussions.
So you see it also created already the claw.md file. If you don't know yet what md means, it is
just a text file that we can open and read again. See, it's just the first file that AI will pick up
and see the instructions. So in this folder we are building a daily journaling database
So if we start talking to AI from within this folder, it will first load in this to understand what the AI should impersonate.
So in this case, it is my personal journaling assistant, if you will. And then it is getting aware that there is a database with these tables and all these things.
And these are the coming queries that come in and so on.
So this is something I wouldn't even open because you don't need to.
But if you want to get the transparency, what's going on behind the scenes with AI,
you can still read this in plain text with natural language for you, easy to understand.
And if there is anything that confuses you, you just copy paste this into Claude and ask about it.
I have no clue what this means.
Or can you give me any additional descriptions inside the cloud.d file as comments to explain more the different sections of these things.
What I just said here, you can just copy in to use as a prompt to ask.
That's really the beauty about working with AI that whenever you hit a wall, just ask it how you can work around it.
And if you're worried about what is going on, you can let AI always double check online if things are working properly.
So now the journaling database is set up.
Here's what's in the folder.
And that's exactly what we have.
And you see how lightweight this is.
So he is now ready whenever you I want to start journaling.
So let's start.
But I want to start on a fresh mind.
OK, so we know that AI doesn't know all about this.
So I show you that it's actually working.
What we can do is slash clear.
This will just clear the conversation and it starts from complete scratch.
And now we can just start talking.
I could just close the terminal and restart the thing.
It would be the same thing and you will see what happens now.
So let's start with the first thing.
journal entry. I just had a meeting today with Paco, our co-founder, and it was amazing because
we talked about how we can further double down on AI productivity for our members inside my I-Core.
And we concluded that the personal area of
productivity is really key here and that's where we will double down more and more and that's why
I decided today to make a video about daily journaling and the advantages people have
using it. Quite a long thing, but we will use this entry very soon. So I just
shared something without even mentioning that this is a journal entry. And now what it will do,
it will go to Claude.md before even answering and thinking about this to load in what this is
all about. And now it has the right context for what I share here. So let's see what happens.
There we go. See? Sounds like an energizing day. Here's what I extracted. Boom, boom, boom. And then I could keep talking to it. So now it started tagging even this entry. And if we go here, there's no image, there's nothing changed. We have this DB that we cannot even open and look at. So how do we access now this information? Where does it live? Well, it lives inside this
database file.
And there could be tools that you can download to visualize this database file.
But the thing is, I don't want to have any additional tools around this.
So I will just say, how can I visualize these channels?
Thanks for the entry.
The thing is, I cannot see these entries yet.
So can you build me a very simple interface that I can open on my Chrome browser to actually see
these journal entries and the metadata insights that you've created for me and also later on the
images that I will share with you in a visually pleasing way and let's think about some colors.
I usually love dark mode colors and so on but I know there are a lot of people who also like light
mode colors so let's
test this for this video.
I'd like to have a light mode interface that is really visually pleasing,
represents a calming way also when you choose the font styles and so on.
So I really enjoy reading these journals.
See, I'm just sharing feelings here.
And maybe somebody would call me out on that and say, well, you're not doing proper prompt engineering, things like that.
Well, I've built a whole MyEye core application, which is our membership with the courses, with community interactions, with many things in there.
only with Claude code in the way that I'm telling you how I interact with AI.
And that's why you can call me out whatever I have proof that the way I'm
doing it is working and it is much simpler than so many people out there suggest.
So again, I will switch to plan mode for this because we are planning out a new
feature and I want to see how he will come up with.
this. While he is thinking about this, keep in mind in the other video I showed you how to build
an AI team. So if you have an AI team, this becomes even more efficient because in an AI team,
you would hire somebody who is just there to do the journaling with you. So in my personal setup,
I have Seneca, which is a stoic mentor that picks up my daily journaling and gives me
feedback on this there.
So this is a specific AI team member.
But I also have an AI developer who is just there to build out new features and things
in my interface and as you can see in this version here it will just create a
simple HTML file that we can double click and open our browser to see everything
that we have in our database. Again I'm just saying don't start with an overkill
and create a team and things like that.
your individual AI assistant here can go a long way.
All you need to understand is that this assistant here is always loading this basic
claw.md file.
And therefore, if you go now beyond daily journaling and you start task management
and many other things that you could do, that is where things become confusing for AI
because everything gets stored inside the claw.md file.
And that is the moment where you need to think about a way to build an AI team and things like that.
based on simple folder structure.
What I'm using here is probably Overkill,
the Opus 4.6 with 1 million context window.
It's very expensive,
running through your tokens very fast.
So if you want to start
and you have no idea yet where it's going,
maybe you switch to Sonnet
the model, which you just do by slash model, and then you can
switch the models and start working this way. It will be also
a lot faster than here waiting for Opus because there is no 1
million context window needed yet. But later on, if you have like
me backfilling my journaling,
from 80 years of journaling
into a database and things like this.
This is where this becomes really powerful
because it gets the full picture
of all the things that you created
and stored over all those years.
Think about it.
If you're using Evernote or anything like this
where you stored all this knowledge,
This is the moment to extract it from these tools and build your own PKA system, which is personal knowledge assistance.
We no longer call it PKM, personal knowledge management, because here I hand over the management to my assistants.
doing the linking the cross-linking and all the things that you will see in the end of the video
how this works in detail. Okay now he is suggesting that he wants to create a Python
architecture plus a single hdml file to open up this thing. It wants really to make an app
out of it instead of just a simple hdml file. I would force now for these videos to
to show you really how simple it is. So if you think this is overkill and I have no clue what's
happening and I wanted to have it simpler, ask it. Let's do this. I don't like an application.
Please just give me a HTML file that shows me the content of the journal database.
So this is the way where we just want to see now the database content and not the
having a proper application.
So later on we can always come back to this and expand the
things when we need any additional fancy features in there.
But right now it's more than enough to just have a fewer HTML
that helps me to visualize.
what is inside the database.
See got it, no server, just plain HTML file and that's it.
This being said, I will make more videos because this no server and so on,
I like code, it scares people away, but it is so much easier than you think.
And you can build your own applications in no time.
And in fact, it will become the future without you knowing what's happening under the hood,
you will be able to create any tools that you want.
And I will show you a lot more how you can build simple tools and apps using AI for your
specific needs.
And that's the key here.
Journal View implementation plan.
See?
refined the plan, we just have an HTML, it's easy to understand the plan, here's what's going, here's the
colors it's using, that's the layout, and that's it. Boom. Very lightweight. So whenever you feel it's too complicated and you have no idea,
Just get back to AI and say: Is there no easier way to make this?
And then you will do it. You will find an easier way for sure.
Okay, so now it's executing the plan.
So it inserts today's journal entry.
It builds the viewer HTML.
Update Claude.md.
So it understands now that there is a viewer available as well.
So it will just add here the information that there is a viewer to show the content and verify viewer in Chrome.
That's what we will do after it finished.
And here we go.
It already opened this up and look how beautiful this looks.
Do you see this is running locally?
There's no, that's not like that.
You need to be afraid that this is now online and other people can see it.
No, it is on your local folder.
You see it, users, Thomas Rödel, my desktop, and here is the daily journaling folder.
And this is the viewer HTML.
If we open up the folder again, desktop, daily journaling, viewer HTML.
So if I double click this, it opens up the exact same thing.
Okay.
That's the amazing thing.
And now look at this.
I have here the first insight that I just said.
You see it took what I said.
It misunderstood my iCorp instead of my iCorp.
It extracted the summary.
Here are the tags.
Here's the energy level and the mood.
It is a light mode and I have even have a search field.
to search for things obviously it's nothing to search here because we will always show this
but i can you know check this mood and filter by it i can see the insights it even created an inside
folder where you already can over time track your mood and energy and this is out of the box
it is a simple html file there's no application behind this
It is just extracting what we will fill in from now onwards into this database.
So if you see something like this where my voice translation was wrong,
you can now always go back and say great start.
but make sure to fix any spelling issues.
One example is my iCorp which should be my iCorp and the rest I'm saying.
And sure to make a glossary where you start tracking any specific names or
words that are uncommon to you.
Add this to the database too as a separate table.
See, this is how I start building additional features on this.
I recognize an issue and now I build a solution for it right on the go.
And what it will do, it will create a new table in the journal.
While he's working, I can already talk to it.
I can say update also the interface.
to show also the glossary.
So we have an individual tab where we can see all the glossary entries.
And then later on, I could say I want to use this interface
to add any glossary entries and things like this.
And this is where it might become more complex.
If you want to enter things into the database, you might need to go beyond
just visualizing it in a simple HTML, but you can really go a long way with the simple one file database view.
So now it created the glossary and the nice thing is if I go here, you see the updates happening live.
See, I just needed to reload and here's the glossary and here's the terms that will be retracted and I guess you will now be adding my iCore.
There we go. See it updated now the embedding.
This looks very complex, but this is just what's happening behind the scenes inside your journal thing here in this viewer HTML.
And there's no magic behind this, even that this is all code.
Again, as I showed you in the other video, if you use Claude Desktop, Cowork and so on, that's what you see there too.
They're just hiding it from you.
so you're not getting confused. But in the end behind the scenes everything works exactly the same
and to me this is just much more transparent to see what's going on. And now if we go to glossary,
boom you see Paco was corrected too in addition to my Eiko. I didn't even mention it but it
recognized it. So the next time he knows when I talk Paco this is it my Eiko and I have this
glossary now. Isn't this amazing? And here are the entries let's see boom it's fixed already.
And this is my first entry here.
Now I want to get one step further and then I let you do the future work and you share whatever you've built in the comments below.
Because it's always amazing what people individually need.
So there is no one template to use for everything.
You are now empowered to build whatever you need.
for yourself using AI. See it tells me then even if you know I'm getting confused with all the code
and so on no it sums it up and if it doesn't you ask what did you just change explain it to me I
have no clue what code is and this is what's happening here. By the way as a small trick here
you can also go to config and in here you can set up
how your cloud will work, cloud code.
And there you can actually go to output style.
And if you hit space, you can now change this from default to explanatory.
So it will explain you a lot more what's doing or even learning.
So it will actually ask you a lot of things that you can actually learn
what it is doing, like coding and so on.
I keep it at default.
But if you're curious what is actually happening, this is the way to go
where you set this to explanatory.
and it will tell you a lot more details about why it's doing what it's doing.
That might be a good way to start the things.
Okay, great. This is working perfectly.
What I would like to have next is also a simple CRM,
a table for my contacts where you keep track of whenever I mention anything
about this person to update their table, like,
whenever I mention a birthday or a phone number or their address or anything like this that you know
where you should store this. So we have always cross-connected links. And then I would also like
that these things get actually clickable in my interface. So whenever a person like Paco is
mentioned, I could click it and I open his card with all the details about him. But also
all the different daily journal entries that mentioned him should
appear on this card too. So I can actually go through them and click again on this mention to
open up this journal entry to read more details about why I mentioned him in this details and also
create a summary on this card. So whenever I mention this person, it will automatically also
update the summary and how I'm connected to this person and so on on the fly. So each time I create
a journal entry with a person mentioned, it should double check if it's
It's worth updating the summary.
Yeah, I think this is about it for now.
You see, now I again go into plan mode for this and let him plan out this.
But now you see what I'm going for.
That's now the difference between PKM and PKA.
In personal knowledge management, if you are on Obsidian, Notion, Heptabase, you name it,
we all learned over the past years how amazing it is to cross connect information.
In fact, that's something we taught over the years too, because you get a lot more insights if you do it, but it's always a lot of friction.
You need to think about it. You don't know how it will be linked in the future because something else comes up.
You forgot about it. That's where a dream was always this auto connecting. But here,
we can now have it perfectly set up in a way that we think it makes sense.
Because now you can imagine here I'm just showing a people database, right?
But you could say next also created a company database
and now connect the people with the company whenever I mentioned them.
And then also you have to cross connections this way.
And AI will keep doing the connections just out of whatever you shared with your natural language, even speaking in whatever you had to share to AI.
And if this is not amazing, I don't know what is.
Because I can tell you, since Paco and I both individually switched, creating our own daily journaling setups like this, the insights we retrieved.
are way beyond whatever we had with our already highly refined productivity systems we had before
that. AI is amplifying any system that you already had in place. And now Paco and I,
we feel it. We had a solid system running, the foundation is right and
Putting AI on top is just accelerating everything, giving you more insights than ever.
And this is the crazy thing.
And what people miss out, they hear about AI, they start using the chatbot and so on, but they don't have no system in place.
And that's why AI keeps failing as if you are confused why you need a system and you're not organized in your daily work and things like that.
AI will be too. You could say, how can I become more productive? AI will give you a thousand
answers what to do. And you might have a great conversation with AI and share some hacks. But the
real beauty is when you have a proper system in place that is already very efficient, and you just
replace individual parts of the system with AI that processes things for you that gave you a lot
of friction in the past. This is the moment where you feel that AI is already changing the way we
work. And anybody saying out there, you have time, it's not there yet, we can stay calm and it's just
hype. It's nonsense.
I can just say it as it is.
You can believe this.
You can stay in this bubble and say everything will be fine and then be
surprised that everybody else is ahead of you or you just start tinkering around
with these things, start with the basics, play around with it.
And you will see with just simple things like this.
how you will improve your overall work.
And this is what the future will be in businesses too,
because it's not the business owner putting AI on top
and forcing everybody to use this AI now.
It will be the individual team member,
the individual employee and the business owner himself
who will have their own AI teams running for them.
Their daily journals connecting information across the company,
if it is allowed, and all these things that will make
the overall company more productive and not the company
forcing people into AI, because as we see, nobody has a clue about AI.
Usually business owner doesn't know why they need to AI and it will end up like everybody's using AI.
So we should use AI.
Here we are and you have it and we have no clue what it is.
And this is not an AI problem.
This is a problem, especially in corporate in bigger companies where they feel forced
to do something like implementing agile thinking and many things like this
without understanding why they actually roll out all these things
and therefore falling short, people start using buzzwords,
but they have no clue why this is in place.
And this gives frustration and confusion.
And that's why the future lays in educating your people
in personal productivity using AI
instead of forcing them to use something
that you probably don't understand yourself.
Something to keep in mind, obviously, if we force everything
in just one simple HTML file, this will blow up things very
quickly. So we can actually open this up here by clicking here.
So you see the content what's inside the file. And you see
there's already a lot of lines of code in there that is just for
visualizing the database. So eventually, if you add more and
more complex features like this, you might end up to build a
very lightweight, simple application. Again,
you will be surprised that there is no code involved and you can go a long way with it.
Just keep in mind when you do things like this, as long as you do these things locally,
no issue, but if you start sharing things and so on, then think twice.
Don't sell these things if you don't know about how to set up security guardrails,
things like that, that your passwords don't get exposed and things like this.
That's really important, but as long you have it here, store it on Dropbox folder locally and therefore it's synced on Google Drive or whatever, or on iCloud.
You have it backed up.
You have your journal app there, just in a folder, very lightweight.
Okay, it updated it.
Let's see what it did.
Here we go.
Now we have a new thing.
Contacts.
Boom.
There is Paco Cantero.
I can click on it.
Boom.
Amazing.
I see here Paco, our co-founder.
Here we see there's no information about him, but he is working company and is a co-founder.
And here's the entry.
And if I click.
here we go it's close to the entry guys and we built this in just one short video that i'm sharing
with here so i hope you can imagine how far we can get so you can see now this is clickable paco
inside boom i can open this up and in another video i can even show you how you can build a
graph like you have an obsidian where everything is just visually representing how things are
interconnected you can do all this yourself you don't need
obsidian that actually changes the files in a way that you cannot use this elsewhere. Here you're
building everything for yourself. You see just in a matter of a few prompts without any background
knowledge necessary and we have all this already working. Let's do one more journal entry and see
how things work now. I clear again.
the knowledge and now I will start saying. Three days ago I talked with Paco about how we can best
update the user experience inside our MyAeco application to make engagement even better.
We had great conversations about this
And meanwhile, we even implemented all this already.
But please add this daily journal entry retrospectively.
And on the same day, later on, I went shopping with my wife.
And as you don't know her yet, my wife is Carolyn.
And I think you get the point.
And let's see what he will do.
Now with this entry, how it gets cross-connected, how he creates now the new CRM entries.
Let's see.
So what he is doing again, he goes now to CloudMD that is now updated.
You see, that's the beauty of VS Code.
I can go to any file and see its content.
And here we see all the content, image storage, all these things.
Oh yeah, image storage, something we didn't test yet.
And I want to show you for sure.
Okay, here it comes back with a question.
My echo.
Okay, so that was a misinterpretation of what I was saying again.
But see, it recognized it.
So I can say it is a misspelling.
It was my I-core.
And my personal assistant, actually for my personal journaling, I'm using German
language and you can use whatever language you use.
Obviously my English is not perfect and it might misread things a lot.
quicker than others native speakers do. But perfect, he
recognized it, he double checks with me if it was correctly
understood. And now it makes the correct entries. Also great for
this video is that we already here and using extra usage. So let's look
at this point of the video, what we are at. So we see the current session is right now at 100%. It
will reset in 17 minutes. And we are currently at 22 euros, which is already from previous sessions
where I went over. So let's just keep this in mind 22 euros. And then we will check later on
when it resets how much we spend while we've been working on this.
Okay, it finished the two entries.
Let's see what happened.
Boom, here we go.
Two new entries.
Late in the day when shopping with my wife, Caroline.
I can click.
It created already these things.
It made a note, Thomas's wife.
And here's the entry.
And now I can keep expanding on it.
And the same is here now, "Talk with Paco", if we open up now we see the two entries appearing here.
And I say, "Oh, Paco, well here and well I already thought about Paco in another context and so on."
And this is how you start cross-connecting all this. Isn't this amazing?
So the last thing I want to test here is sharing screenshots and then add this to my daily channel, how this already works.
So I have this in short and it's just in my clipboard, right?
And I will just paste this into the chat where we celebrate now that we have 3000 members
already inside my iCore.
This is amazing.
Thanks so much, guys, for joining our membership.
We are growing rapidly right now.
And this is what we paste in.
You see, it says image.
That's all I need.
So I just copy paste it in with command V from my clipboard.
And now I just give more context.
Today we are celebrating 3000 members inside my iCore.
This is amazing and we are so happy that what we teach is helping so many members already
and we are obviously hoping that we will get a lot more members in because engaging with these
people inside the membership is just amazing seeing what people are building this is amazing
and being on this journey together towards using AI for productivity is something that Paco and I
both deeply enjoy okay there we go so now we have the image in front and I have the text and let's
see what it will do what a milestone and it gets the screenshot it found the count of members and
can read images, it can extract data from these images and makes the thing. So now it asks me if
this looks all right. If I'm getting more and more confident, I might even say, do whatever
you want, don't get back to me and so on. So I just say yes in this case, and
This is what we'll get created now.
Now we see images and here's the image.
Boom.
It is locally stored again.
You can always right click here and say reveal in finder and it opens up the folder.
Again, desktop, daily journaling, images.
Here's your image. It's a PNG file. It's just a local file.
But with the power that this will get now connected inside your database with the context and it will be visualized in a different way.
And this is the powerful thing that even if you're not happy with this interface anymore,
You could just build something from scratch.
Nothing gets lost.
All your data remains active.
And this is makes you independent from any tool switching, losing your information along the way.
So the powerful thing is if I would be on the go and I want to talk with my daily journal, I can always go here remote.
slash remote and go to remote control and it will create and launch a remote control and now you can
just use the cloud mobile application to access exactly this chat so i could now just go here and
write something and it will just appear right in here is
if I would be sitting on my computer writing with it.
And this is where you can be on the go and simply just keep sharing images, talking,
and it will create these entries on the go.
Again, no other tool needed.
You just use Claude for this.
Boom, it created the entry.
Let's see what happened on the front end.
Here we go. And there we see that it's not showing the image properly. It extracted everything from
the image. It mentioned Paco. See, it works. I can click and I see now three entries for Paco.
But for this, again, it's not working. So what's the thing? Well,
Many things that you can do, you can just talk.
But what I prefer is that I just make a screenshot from this
situation here, how this looks and share it back with AI like
this and say, as you can see, the image is not showing properly
on the interface that you've built.
Can you fix this, please?
I have some ideas why this is but most people don't and that's the approach you would do it.
I could also say instead of sharing the image I could say go to Chrome and check for yourself
until it's working. So it would go to Chrome using the Chrome extension as I showed you in another
video on this channel and make screenshots for himself to understand if it's working and it
keeps improving things until it's working.
Here we might have a back and forth where it tries things, but I guess you get it right now.
So if I reload, it asks me to allow and here we go.
There's the image, I can open it up, see full screen image.
Isn't this amazing?
Now we have the daily journal entry with an image available.
And this is the moment where I will stop this implementation and we'll now talk about how could we now merge this back
into our existing AI team that we already created earlier.
So obviously, if you just watch this video and you created this, you could go from here.
Or if you now watch the previous video and you created the AI team,
this is how you can bring things together now.
So keep in mind, we are here in the daily journaling folder.
Let's move to another folder.
So I just say a new window and I will open up in this window now.
the PKA demo that we created earlier as you see with these things.
So you see now on the side just the content again.
So we have both folders open independently.
And if I launch now a cloud in here, we are now working inside this folder and not in this folder.
So what I want to do now as we had here already a journal created so just as a reminder if we open up now this file inside Chrome this is what we built previously and here was already a journal with an entry so now we have two different databases but we like this one much more.
I actually do like this much more what we built here. And now is the moment where you really see
how AI can shine with this. So I'm here and I can now just say, let's go to this folder that we just
created daily journaling, right click, and I hold on option to get the path name. I could also just
drag and drop this in here and hold shift so you get the link to it so there are two ways to do this
and I say we've just created this new journaling approach in another folder
that I really like and I would like you to implement this
in our PKA demo folder.
We already have some journaling
basics there and we already have created
an interface, but please look at this
new version that I like much more.
Also the looks of it.
I want to have this upgraded in the
overall interface.
going from this brownish color to the light mode version.
But also make sure that you compare the different databases,
make sure to migrate the content that we already created in the previous folder
and update our current folder with it and understand how things are interconnected
how things are working in this new version and carefully update our current
version here with this new approach.
So we can end up deleting the other folder and just keep using the journaling
approach in this folder. As you see,
there was a lot of rambling that I did here.
You can also write this down to be sure you're doing it right for the purpose of
sharing. I do it this way now. And again, I switch to plan mode
for this, he will load in his Claude.com file that we created
in a previous video. And let's see what happens. Again, in plan
mode, nothing will crack break. This is exactly the approach.
And then you can still decide if you will do changes or if you
feel that there's more things that you need to look into. But
what it will do, it might also use our team. Okay, so we have team
members.
Sable is the one that we hired in the past video who is our developer.
So he should now hand this off to Sable in order to work on this.
So first he's exploring everything.
We could have said the team should work on this.
That usually triggers that he really is using the team.
We can reinforce and guardrail that he's not allowed to use this, but he needs to hand this off.
We could have said Nolan, the HR person in the team, should hire another person who is
focused on databases and understands migrations and things like that.
That's what I would do in this too.
So he actually has a specific AI team member who is focused on just this type of work and
you will get even better outcomes.
But I'm pretty sure as long the things are so small as they are here, it will do a
pretty good job to make the migration work without any extra AI member hired. Just keep this in mind,
if you have more complex things, this would be the way I would do it. I would hire a specific
person who was specialized in the work that needs to get done, because this will upfront
do a lot more research about how things should get done and then you have a proper team member that
you always can address the work to. While this is working on it I will open up again the usage
to see what's happening. So we had 22 euros if I reload we see now they updated.
costs. Okay, all the things that we did so far up to this
point was just one euro. So you get just an idea of the costs.
And I think this is okay, especially as this is now
resetting in three minutes, I'm no longer spending any extra
usage. And I'm back in my normal $200
plan. And the same applies for the pro plan or the $100 max plan. Okay, and that's the beautiful
thing. While he is thinking, it shows you the insights already, it compared already the new daily
journaling versus the current implementation of this. And now he creates the migration plan. And
that's where if you see any templates or anything that you can download, that might be a good way to do this too. Let's
your existing AI agent, review what else there is and see how it can get
incorporated in your existing setup rather than just switching to something
random that another person created.
Now we see it just switched back to the normal plan without anything me doing
while he is working, there's no interruption or whatever.
So it just keeps working on the same thing.
And here we go, there is the plan that he created.
Again, by the way, you could say now, hey, can you give me this plan in a PDF format and in a nice formatted way so I can calmly read through it?
All the things are possible if this is too confusing to you.
But here, this is what he will do.
Database migration.
It will migrate our other database into this current one.
It will even make a backup first of the one that you have in place.
See, amazing approach.
That's really proactivity that I really love.
about Claude here. And it adds the missing column, see, like birthday address
summary that we haven't had in our current PKA system yet. Create new
tables, the entry context, the images, and the glossary. See, that's
something we haven't had. So it recognized all the things. It imports the
four journals that we made in the new version into this current version.
It shows me exactly what it will work on the different files, doing exports,
and then it updates the viewer with our new approach of the visualization.
And then it does the data injections of all the things.
So nothing we need to worry about.
I will just let it work.
And you see this is working now.
So you see it's delegating to Sable, our team member here, where he delegates the update of all the things now.
So Larry will delegate a full implementation to sell this plan.
So you see the thing that we built in the previous video is working, right?
Larry is recognizing that he needs to delegate this over to Sable.
And Sable is now the guy working on it.
He's saying it plan approved, time to get to work.
I'm sending this to Sable.
She built the current PK viewer and knows the architecture inside out, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Okay, and now you see Larry launches a sub-agent and this sub-agent is called Sable.
So it is really recognizing even that we are not using proper agents here. That's something we just
have in the back end. We have here team roaster and if you watch the previous video we built this
from scratch and it's just all based on normal files. So if we open up Sable here we see what
she can do and how she approaches things and where to find additional information.
And then out of this it's cross-connected to this agent that
shares a lot more details about what we can do and where to find additional information and so on.
But this is managed by Larry. So I don't have to worry about this. All I need to worry about is
staying here in the chat and keep interacting with Larry. And if things go wrong, readjust and say
update any relevant information and things like this.
I'm doing this since last year June and I'm doing a lot more complex things than what you see me building here.
And it never failed. It never failed.
The real skill that people need to learn is how to ask the right questions.
This is really the thing that people need to learn in the new generations too.
Asking right questions and team management, I think.
Everything that we teach in my ICO based on the ICO methodology, tool agnostic and gives you a tool agnostic understanding of your productivity system end to end, which is the foundation of any AI tool that we are building here, but also building businesses and managing teams. It's all based on the ICO methodology.
So if you're not a member yet, this is the moment to join.
Okay, and here we go.
It's finished.
Let's see what it looks now on the front end.
And here we go.
Beautiful.
This is now light mode.
It's no longer dark mode as we had before the brown one, if you remember, which was this one.
So this if I reload this page, it will now switch to this mode too.
I have this journal.
We see here is the entrance that we just created with the image.
It's perfectly working.
I have here the connection to Paco.
It opens up Paco with all the context available.
I have here the contacts that go beyond Paco already, but it added Paco and my wife too.
It even shows me here Paco three journal mentions.
So you see how everything gets perfectly integrated.
And now I could have here the meeting notes and it starts connecting the people and all these things.
and talking about meeting nodes, one of the upcoming videos will be exactly about this:
How you leverage your meeting node transcripts in the best way possible to enrich your PKA system
on autopilot. This is, that's a real game changer. So if you haven't subscribed,
to subscribe now or join us in my iCore to stay connected or access any of our courses or even our
coaching course that we have on a weekly basis with Paco and me if you need any additional
assistance with your PKA system. I catch you up in the next one.